中文字幕來源: R3-DVD 香港譯本
本條字幕匹配109分鐘的導演剪輯版
The Cell (2000)
For Director's Cut
109min
片名: 入 侵 腦 細 胞 港譯: 移 魂 追 兇 台譯: 死 亡 空 間
謝謝你把馬借給我
Thank you for the horse.
- 你喜歡它嗎?  - 它好美
- You liked him? - Oh, it's beautiful.
不過我還以為今天是去玩帆船
But I thought we were going sailing today.
你答應過的
You promised.
那艘太舊了
Well, that one's too old.
看  那艘就可以了
See, now? That'll do.
過來呀
Come on.
過來嘛  艾華
Come on, Mr. E.
- 船是破的  - 誰說的?
- It's broken. - Who says?
莫基洛
Mokelock.
艾華  你答應過不再提莫基洛的
Now, Edward, we agreed. No more Mokelock.
莫基洛就是那怪物
Mokelock is the bogeyman.
- 莫基洛想我留在這裏  - 我們可以修好它的
- Mokelock wants me where I am. - We can fix it.
艾華
Edward.
唱"六便士歌"給我聽聽
Sing a song of sixpence.
一整袋的黑麥
CATHERINE: A pocket full of rye.
二十四隻黑鳥
MIRIAM: Four and 20 blackbirds.
放在批裏面烤
CATHERINE: Baked in a pie.
起床吧
MIRIAM: Rise and shine.
艾華看來不錯
Mr. E is doing fine.
你倆有沒有揚帆出海?
Did we go sailing?
幾乎去了
Almost.
- 但莫基洛出現了  - 莫基洛是怪物
- Mokelock showed up. - Mokelock is the bogeyman.
他想我留在這裏
Mokelock wants me where I am.
莫基洛真是煩死人
Mokelock is a pain in the ass.
- 他從哪裏想出這個莫基洛?  - 鵝媽媽兒歌集
- HENRY: Where'd he get Mokelock again? - CATHERINE: Mother Goose.
- 亨利  - 貝裏
- BARRY: Henry. - HENRY: Barry.
什麼事  貝裏?
What's the matter, Barry?
艾華的父母來了
Edward's, uh, parents are here.
(甘保中心)
他需要剪頭髮了
MRS. BAINES: He needs a haircut.
他很喜歡你來探他
CATHERINE: He loves it when you visit.
我丈夫懷疑這是不是真的
My husband wonders if that's true.
他想送艾華入醫院
He wants to place Edward in a hospital.
對不起  嘉芙
I'm sorry, Catherine.
包先生
HENRY: Mr. Baines.
我已花了七年時間在這個計劃上
I've been working on this project for seven years.
我知道  亨利  我知道
I know, Henry. I know.
請不要見怪
Please don't take offense, Dr. Kent.
- 你的工作很有價值  - 但你懷疑我
- Your work's invaluable to this company. - But you're not sure about me.
我們等進展等了十八個月
We've waited, uh, 18 months for signs of progress.
- 的確有進展啊  - 但沒有證據
- There has been progress. - There's no proof, Catherine.
不怕得罪
With all due respect, Mr. Baines...
程序不是我設計的
...I'm not the one who designed the procedure.
我但願這可以歸功於我
I wish I could take credit for it, but I can't.
我只是被他們選中做一份工作
I was chosen to do a job. They picked me.
如果你認為有人會更合適
But if you think there's someone better...
或者有人對你兒子會更好
...or someone who's more devoted to your son, then--
沒有人懷疑你的能力
No one's doubting your ability.
- 那為什麼  - 沒有證據  嘉芙
- What is it, then? - MR. BAINES: There's no proof, Catherine.
沒有證據顯示這個程序有用
There's no proof the procedure works.
你只是告訴我
All you're giving me is the belief...
你相信跟我兒子的接觸不是
...that your interaction with my son is not a...
幻覺
...hallucination.
我還是回去工作好了  再見  包太
I better get back to work. Goodbye, Mrs. Baines.
- 謝謝你  - 謝謝  謝謝你  包先生
- Thank you. - Thank you. Thank you, Mr. Baines.
MR. BAINES: Come, shall we? Lucien.
我們走吧
- 幸好她崇拜你  - 因為他恨我
- Lucky she worships you. - Why? Because he hates me?
我不會說是"恨"  是不信任  很不喜歡
I wouldn't say "hates." Distrusts, dislikes immensely...
不想見到
...can't bear the sight of.
裁決是什麼?
What's the verdict?
我們還有六個月
Well, we've got another six months...
貝裏花了很多唇舌說服他
...and Barry had to push for that.
我想艾華倒過來進入我的世界  比以往更想
I wanna reverse the feed, Miriam, now more than ever.
我們討論過一百次了  那太危險
We've been through this a hundred times, Catherine. It's too risky.
為什麼?  我們有什麼可損失的?
Why not? What do we have to lose?
在我做社工時
When I did social work, it was always better...
把孩子帶離他本身的環境會更好
...when we took the kids out of their environment.
孩子初入寄養家庭會很害怕
Foster homes can be scary at first...
但最後事情總會好轉
...but eventually they see things can be different.
艾華現在就是那個情況
Edward is like that right now.
他處身在一個不健康的環境中
He's living in a world that is not healthy.
- 我們應該帶他去別處  - 假設我們依照你的方法做
- Let's show him a different place. - All right. Let's say we do it your way.
把艾華帶進你的內心世界
We reverse the feed and we bring Edward into your mind.
他發現被塞進別的世界
Can you imagine his shock when he finds...
肯定會被嚇壞的
...he's been thrust into this whole other world?
- 我也經常這麼做  - 但你是自願的
- I do it all the time. - Yes, but you're a willing participant, Catherine.
你知道會發生什麼事  但艾華是在昏迷中
You're aware of what's happening. Edward's in a coma.
而且我們還未知道這對你的影響
And besides, we don't know what effect it will have on you.
你已筋疲力竭了
I mean, you're already exhausted.
-  你有沒有睡覺?  - 有
- Have you been sleeping? - Yes.
- 還有沒有發噩夢?  - 沒有
- Any more nightmares? - No.
- 沒有  - 那就好了
- No. - Good.
把工作留在這裏  別帶回家
Leave work here. Don't take it home in this.
嘿  你好啊
Hey, you.
你在找什麼?
What are you looking for? Hmm?
想喝牛奶嗎?
Want some milk?
艾華
CATHERINE: Edward.
艾華  是你嗎?
CATHERINE [THINKING]: Edward, is that you?
你出海時  有沒有見到
Edward, were there seals being killed on the beach...
海豹被殺?
...while you were sailing?
別躲  甜心  艾華  是你嗎?
Don't hide, sweetie, please? Edward, is that you?
別怕  沒有人會傷害你
Don't be afraid. No one will hurt you.
艾華  是你嗎?
Edward, is that you?
睡吧
Go to sleep.
爸爸
WOMAN: Daddy!
救命呀
Help"
Somebody, help me!
救命呀
WOMAN: Help me!
- 謝謝你等我  高爾  - 別客氣
- Thanks for waiting, Cole. - Teddy Lee, no problem.
聯邦密探林西
Special Agent Ramsey.
- 我是高爾  - 早安
- Cole. - Morning.
誰發現她的?
Who found her?
鐵路的測量員  今早六時左右
COLE: The surveyor for the railroad, about 6 this morning.
剎車痕跟雷諾裸屍案的一樣
Skid marks appear to match the tire tracks from Reno.
似乎撞到欄杆  刮下了一點車漆
And it looks like he scraped the rail, lost some paint too.
車漆已送去化驗
It's on its way to the lab already.
屍體被棄置在這邊
Dumped the body over there.
漂白水
Bleach.
衛安妮  第七名受害人
RAMSEY: Anne Marie Vicksey. She makes seven.
我的天
Jeez, this stinks.
- 她們全都看來像洋娃娃?  - 是的
- Do they all look like dolls? - TEDDY: Every unfortunate soul.
- 那是什麼?  - 頸圈之類
- COLE: What's that? - Some kind of a collar.
- 那是他的手法之一  - 他戴上去的?
- Part of his methodology. - The way he puts it there?
他為她們造的
He makes it for them.
這令他覺得她們屬於他
It makes him feel they belong to him.
水位通常都這麼低嗎?
NOVAK: ls the water always this low?
是的  每年這個時候都是
Yeah, this time of year.
立刻給我驗屍報告  還有初步化驗報告
Give me a coroner's report right away. Preliminary forensics too.
任何人都不得拖延這宗案件
I don't want anyone dragging their ass on this.
- 工作怎麼樣?  - 精疲力竭
- So how was work? - Ugh. Exhausting.
我也沒主意  珍妮
RAMSEY: I have no idea, Jeannie. For God's sake.
祝你好運  我也愛你  我要掛線了
Good luck with the monster. I love you too. Gotta go.
- 好的  謝謝  拜  - 好吧  拜拜
- JEANNIE [OVER PHONE]: Okay. Thanks. Bye. - All right. Bye-bye.
剛出爐的報告
Hot off the presses.
各位  沒有新的消息可報告了
TEDDY: Oh. There's nothing new to report, gentlemen.
精液吻合
A match on his semen.
她肺中的水
Water in her lungs...
含有大量氯氣和鐵銹
...show high levels of chlorine and rust.
請問這是什麼?
What pray tell is this?
他們說發現了狗毛?
They say they found some dog hair?
- 是警犬嗎?  - 不  不是警犬
- From a K-9 unit? - No. There was no K-9 unit.
而且衛安妮沒有養狗
And Anne Vicksey doesn't own a dog, Teddy.
我想看清楚這根狗毛
I wanna see this.
你想找什麼?
What you got, Teddy?
哼
TEDDY: Hmm.
白蝕
Hypomelanosis.
那是什麼意思?
And that means?
完全沒有黑色素
A complete absence of melanin.
那隻狗有白化病
The dog is an albino.
他喜歡那樣的動物
He'd love an animal like that.
各位
TEDDY: Gentlemen...
我相信白蝕的狗是很罕見的
...I believe an albino dog is a rare animal indeed.
我的天
Oh, my God.
你不會有事的
You're gonna be okay.
乖乖  對不起
Baby, I'm so sorry.
老天爺  彼得
Jesus Christ, Peter.
我以為你會睡一會  清潔一下吧
Thought you were gonna get some sleep, clean yourself up.
清潔好了
I did.
- 他們在等  - 我預備好了
- They're waiting, you know. - I'm ready.
那麼我們走吧
Let's go. Ahem.
我們分兩頭進行
NOVAK: We're gonna do this two ways.
聯絡狼狗養殖場
Breeders of German shepherds.
福特代理商
Ford dealers.
調查要徹底  行動要快
I want you to be thorough, and I also want you to be fast.
這個人出動得越來越頻密了  今次他只等了六天
This guy's accelerating. He only waited six days this time.
他開始時隔幾個月才犯一次案  這有兩個可能
When he first started, months could pass. And that means one of two different things.
一  他以為我們蠢得抓不到他
One, he thinks we're stupid and we can't catch him.
二  我相信是這個  他想被捕
Two, which is the one that I believe, he wants to be caught.
留下狗毛太大意了
The dog hair thing is sloppy.
他把衛安妮棄置在水深三寸之處
He leaves Anne Marie Vicksey in three inches of water.
明知我們會發現她
He knew that we'd find her.
有一件事是肯定的
Now, there's one thing I know for certain.
如果我們制止不到他
If we can't stop him...
他自己無法制止自己
...he ain't gonna stop himself.
這張照片可以嗎?
Will this be all right?
可以了  謝謝你
Yes, ma'am, that's great. Thank you very much.
她仍然住在家裏嗎?
She was still, uh, living at home, ma'am?
我們正在找房子
We were looking for apartments.
但他們在結婚前不會搬進去
But they're not moving in together until after the wedding.
茱莉想結婚
Julia wants to be married.
她有沒有提及過不尋常的事?
Did she ever mention anything out of the ordinary?
例如最近認識的人
For instance, somebody she recently met...
或是否有人跟蹤她?
...or somebody perhaps watching her, following her?
沒提過
No.
不好意思
Pardon me.
林西
Ramsey.
如果是你弄錯了呢?
WOMAN: What if you made a mistake?
也許不是那個人  也許她很安全
Maybe this isn't the man. Maybe Julia's safe.
他的某些行徑
There's certain things that he does...
令我們頗為肯定是他做的
...that, uh, make us pretty positive that this is the man.
去年我丈夫癌癥過身了
WOMAN: Last year, I lost my husband to cancer.
他痛得要命  但茱莉總在他身旁
I went through such terrible pain. But Julia, she was always there for me.
什麼事  林西?
What's going on, Gordon?
河濱區警方在林峰找到一個狗場
Riverside sheriff found a dog breeder in Woodcrest.
三年前賣出過一隻白蝕小狼狗
Three years ago, she had a buyer for an albino shepherd pup.
據運輸署紀錄  買主開一輛福特
Sheriff checks DMV. Son of a bitch drives a '92 Ford pickup.
- 猜那是什麼顏色的  - 水綠色
- Guess what color. - Aqua green.
林西
Ramsey!
- 彼得  - 他在哪裏?
- Novak! - Where is he?
愛迪信街
Edison, just east of Lorna Park.
特種部隊已監視了那處四十分鐘
SWATs had the house under surveillance for about 20 minutes.
史卡萊  沒有登記武器  沒案底
Carl Rudolph Stargher. No registered weapons, no priors.
狗倒有領牌  叫華倫泰
Got a license for his dog, though. Named him Valentine.
哈
Ha!
你就是兇手吧  是嗎  卡萊?
You're the bad man. Aren't you, Carl?
你會嗎?
Would you?
我的天
[GRUNTING AND GASPING]
[DISTORTED VOICE SPEAKING]
我的天  醒過來
林西探員  彼得探員
Brock, Agent Ramsey, Agent Novak.
我們已盡快趕來  他們已知情況
We got here as fast as we could. I briefed them on the way over.
現況如何?
Where do we stand?
現在的情況是
Here's the situation.
我在屋頂上派駐了一隊人員
We got a high-ground team on the roof...
東面有四名武裝隊員
...a four-man element to the east.
貨車上有破門部隊
We got an entry team in the van across from the house...
南面有兩人
...a two-man element to the south.
- 你們見到他沒有?  - 還沒有
- Have you seen him yet? - No.
廚房裏有些動靜  但看不出是誰
There's been some movement in the kitchen. Can't tell what it is.
- 你認為她在裏面嗎?  - 當她在吧
- RAMSEY: You think the girl's in there? - NOVAK: We'll proceed assuming that she is.
- 聯邦密探  聯邦密探  - 快
- AGENT 1: FBI! FBI! - AGENT 2: Go!
別動  雜種
Freeze, motherfucker!
聯邦密探
MAN 3: FBI! FBI!
我找到那隻狗了
I got the dog!
- 沒有人  - 沒有人
- Clear. - Clear.
送他去縣醫院  李德已經在那裏
They'll take him to County General. Reid's already there.
一定要用手銬  兩個人看守
Make sure he stays cuffed. I want two men on him at all times.
不准李德以外的任何人治理他
I don't want anyone to treat him but Reid.
塞一支探熱針入他屁股都不行
Not so much as a thermometer up his ass, understand?
是
Mm.
- 彼得  她不在這裏  - 是的
- Peter, she's not here. - Yeah.
你該下來看看
You should, uh, come downstairs.
(漂白水)
(你有病嗎?)
(雕刻家)
媽咪
WOMAN: Mommy!
幫我照顧孩子
Please take care of my little baby!
喂?  喂?
Hello? Hello?
求求你  你在嗎?  喂?
Please, is there anybody there? Hello?
你聽到我說話嗎?
Can you hear me?
喂?
Hello?
我沒看見你的臉
I didn't see your face.
我沒看見
I didn't see...
你的任何一面
...any part of you.
這不是真的
This is not happening to me.
難以置信
I can't believe this is happening.
你們有沒有聽過惠倫氏癥?
Have you ever heard of Whelan's infraction?
是一種精神分裂  很罕見  也很嚴重
It's a form of schizophrenia. It's very rare, and it's very severe.
精神分裂的人  這些部分會受侵襲
In any schizophrenic, these areas would be affected...
但惠倫氏癥的人特別嚴重和快速
...but in someone with Whelan's, they're hit hard and they're hit fast.
不能給他大量鎮靜劑或精神藥嗎?
Can't you load him up with Thorazine or Desoxyn?
普通治療精神病的藥沒有用
REID: Normal psychotropics don't work.
病因是病毒在子宮感染神經系統
This thing is caused by a virus that infects the neurological system in utero.
它一直蟄伏  直至有創傷引發
It lays dormant until it's triggered by some kind of trauma.
他的病癥可能已出現了一段時間
Most likely, he's exhibited symptoms for some time...
但到今天才真正病發
...but the infraction, or the breach, didn't occur till today.
引發的因素有很多
The triggers can vary.
通常都與水有關  但結果都一樣
Uh, usually water-related, but the results don't vary.
他不只是患上緊張癥
He's not just catatonic.
他是消失了  就像做夢  而且永遠醒不過來一樣
He's disappeared. Like having a dream and never waking up.
- 這會維持多久?  - 永遠
- For how long? - Oh, forever.
我想我們沒提到最重要那點
Lee, I think we might be missing the bigger picture here.
無論他是在何種狀態
Now, whatever state that he happens to be in...
仍有一名女子失蹤  她叫賀茱莉
...there is a girl that is missing and her name is Julia Hickson...
而他是唯一知道她在哪裏的人
...and he is the only one that knows where she is.
他把她們藏在密室裏約四十小時
He keeps them in this thing for about 40 hours.
他是在昨晚七時半擄走賀茱莉的
Now, he took Julia Hickson at 7:30 last night.
彼得  你知道我的為人  如果有任何事  任何事
Peter, you know me. If there were anything, anything...
什麼?
What?
他給她們食物  水  還有廁所
He provides them with food, drinking water and a toilet.
她們以為只是綁架  不一定會死
Now, she thinks she's been kidnapped, that there's a chance of survival...
但這只是一種折磨
...but it's just a form of torture.
這對他來說是一個潔淨儀式  之後再帶她們回家
This is a kind of ritual for him, a cleansing before he takes them home...
把受害者造成玩偶  變成玩具
...and turns them into a doll, a toy.
密室是完全自動化的
Now, this thing is fully automated...
除非我們今晚之前找到她
...and unless we find her by tonight...
否則她也會遭遇同一命運
...this will happen to her.
關於這次聯合行動
At the request of Mr. Cooperman...
我們聯絡過你們的董事局
...we've contacted your board of directors.
他們已經批准
And they've given their approval.
艾華的父母也批准了
And so have Edward's parents.
不過決定權仍在你們
But the decision is yours.
亨利?
Henry?
好
Yes.
- 美琳?  - 由嘉芙決定吧
- Miriam? - It's up to Catherine.
她才是要面對真正危險的人
She's the one who'd have to face whatever risks there might be...
她作的任何決定我都會支持
...so I support whatever decision she makes.
- 我可以問你一個問題嗎?  - 請便
- Can I ask you something? - Please.
如果他不是昏迷不醒
If he wasn't like this, if he was conscious...
你認為他會說出茱莉的所在嗎?
...do you think that he would tell you where she is?
罪犯總是有懺悔的可能的
There's always a chance of a confession. Yeah.
他的行為顯示他需要讓人知道
And there's things he's done that show a need for disclosure.
只是沒有人願意聽
He hasn't had a sympathetic ear.
他想有人聽他說話  明白他
He wants someone to listen, to, uh, try and understand him.
我很同情這位女士  這是真的
Look, I feel for this girl, I do...
可是史卡萊可能已不知道真相
...but Stargher may no longer know the truth.
因為
For severe schizophrenics...
嚴重精神分裂者分不開真假
...there's no discerning between fantasy and reality.
- 他有可能說出真相嗎?  - 如果他信任我  是有可能的
- Is it possible? - If he came to trust me, yes...
不過贏取這種信任需要幾個月
...but it takes months to earn that kind of trust.
他有可能說出真相嗎?
Is it possible?
爸爸?
WOMAN [ON VIDEO]: Daddy?
我是爸爸的乖女
I'm your little baby. Baby...
爸爸
Daddy.
Daddy!
我是你女兒啊
I'm daddy's girl.
他的層級太深了
His levels are too flat.
- 這裏怎麼了?  - 我們除去了十四個鋼環
- MIRIAM: What happened here? - We removed 14 steel rings.
應該讓他保持原狀的
Should have left him the way he was.
他喜歡吊起自己吧?
He used to suspend himself, didn't he?
是的
Yeah.
精神分裂的人喜歡無重的感覺
They're comforted by the feeling of weightlessness...
就像浮在水中似的
...like floating in water.
各位  這是催化劑
Now this, gentlemen, is the catalyst.
名為神經染色體結合轉移系統
The neurological connectic transfer system...
它不單止描繪出內心世界
...not only maps the mind...
還將訊號傳送到另一個個體
...it sends the signal to another party.
接收者只需調較到適當的頻道
All you need to do is tune in...
調較之後
...but you do much more than tune in.
接收者便變成其內心世界一部分
You become part of the show.
他已經準備好了
MIRIAM: He's ready.
為什麼有三個平台?
Why are there three stations?
我們嘗試進行聯合療法
We tried joint therapy sessions...
用兩個心理學家  但艾華不喜歡
...two shrinks for the price of one, but Edward hated it...
他只肯跟嘉芙說話  她有天份
...and only talked to Catherine. She has a gift.
你肯定要這樣做嗎?
Are you sure?
我肯定
I'm sure.
好吧
Okay.
反應信號
Response signal.
正在操作
Functioning.
我們在她手中植入了微型晶片
We implanted a touch-sensitive microchip in her hand...
如果她想停止或受不了
...so if she wants to stop the session...
按動晶片  我們便會
...or if it gets too intense, she can give the signal...
將過程中止
...and we abort.
當初我們預備好要實際測試時
When we were ready for practical testing...
我們見過
...Miriam and I auditioned...
很多優秀兒童心理學家
...some of the best child therapists in the country.
他們只是觀察  然後匯報
And all they did was observe and report, nothing more.
嘉芙經驗最淺  但備受推崇
HENRY: Catherine was the least experienced, but she came so highly recommended...
我們決定姑且讓她一試
...that we decided, what the hell, we'll give her a shot...
我們立刻便發現她與眾不同
...and immediately, we could tell she was different.
你不是人類  你不該待在我的房子裏
MAN: You're not human. You don't lie in my house.
你是動物  這是我的房子
You're an animal! This is my house.
嘿
Hey!
嘿  你好啊
Hey, you.
你喜歡人輕拍你吧  對嗎?
Yeah, you like that, don't you?
你的名字是卡萊嗎?
Is your name Carl?
我認識一個男孩也有馬
You know, I know another little boy with a horse.
叫艾華  那孩子叫艾華  不是那隻馬
His name's Edward. I mean the boy, not the horse.
有什麼不妥?
What's wrong?
他殺死的人
His victims.
你從哪裏來的?
Where do you come from?
- 喂  - 各位  她回來了
- Yeah. - HENRY [OVER PHONE]: Gentlemen, she's back.
我立刻過來
I'll be right there.
沒事了  別怕  嘉芙
MIRIAM: All right. Come on, Catherine.
她的旅程很特別
HENRY: She's had quite a journey.
跟以往不同
Unlike anything we've ever seen before.
- 那麼她接觸到他了?  - 是的
- So she's made contact? - Oh, yes.
她進入了他內心深處  太深了
She's gone very deep into his world. At times too far.
- 很冷  - 那很危險
- It's cold. - HENRY: That can be dangerous.
你在說什麼?
What are you talking about?
她若相信史卡萊的世界是真的
Well, if she came to believe that Stargher's world is real...
她的心便會說服她的身體
...then theoretically, her mind could convince her body...
在那裏  發生在她身上的事
...that anything that was done to it there...
便是真的
...is actually done.
就像坊間迷信  如果你在夢中夢見自己死去
It's like the old wives' tale where you die in your dream...
那你真的會在現實中死亡
...you die in real life.
提高這裏的溫度可以嗎?
Henry, could you raise the temperature in here?
- 靳醫生?  - 請你等一等
- Dr. Kent? - MIRIAM: Just a moment, please.
請問我可以和你談談嗎?
Can I come in there and speak with her?
你要有耐性
We have to be patient.
看看她  昏昏欲睡  讓她醒過來
I mean, look at her. She's drowsy. Let her wake up.
我們沒有很多時間  你明白嗎?
We don't have a lot of time. Do you understand that?
我們在天上的父
Our Father, who art in heaven...
願人都尊你的名為聖
...hallowed be thy name.
天國福音降臨於世
Thy kingdom come, thy will be done, on earth as it is in heaven.
我有沒有打擾你們?
NOVAK: Am I interrupting anything?
我可以坐下來嗎?
Is it okay if I...?
他知道你來了  是嗎?
He knows you're here, doesn't he?
我朋友李德醫生說
My friend, uh, Dr. Reid, said...
這麼小的孩子  罹患精神分裂
...that it's very unusual, uh, schizophrenia that is...
- 是很罕見的  - 醫生一般會以為是自閉癥
- ...in a child that's this young. - They usually think it's autism.
你得明白他的身體沒有問題
What you have to understand is there's nothing wrong with his body.
癱瘓的是他一部分的心智
What's paralyzed is a part of his mind.
心智受病毒侵害  以致他不能動
It's so damaged by the virus he can't even will himself to move.
你認為你可以改變現狀嗎?
You think you can change that?
你相信你內心有一部分
Do you believe there's a part of yourself...
是你永遠不會示人的嗎?
...that you don't show anybody?
我想人人都有那一部分
I think everybody has that side of themselves.
在實驗中  我進入別人的心靈時
During a session, when I'm inside...
我便見到這一部分
...I get to see those things.
我感覺到它們
I feel them.
在卡萊的內心  我感覺到一種我不想再有的感覺
With Stargher, I felt things I never wanna feel again.
他甚至不再是史卡萊
He's not even Carl Stargher anymore.
他是一個理想化了的自己  是一個變態王國的王帝
He's this idealized version of himself, a king in a very, very twisted kingdom.
在那裏他可以盡情墮落
It's the place for him to indulge every...
我不想在這兒談這些事
You know, I don't wanna talk about this in here.
我永遠做不到你所做的
I could never do what you do...
全心全意去瞭解這樣的心靈
...devote myself to understanding a mind like that.
我不認為我終會瞭解他的內心
I don't think we'll ever be able to understand a mind like that.
可是你嘗試  那是你的工作
But you try. That's your job.
我想是吧
I guess so.
- 你不喜歡你的工作嗎?  - 比起上一份工作  我較喜歡這份
- You don't like what you do? - I like it better than my old job.
我以前是律師  當檢察官
Used to be an attorney. I was a prosecutor.
發生了什麼事?
What happened?
我有宗案件  一個小女孩遭非禮
I had a case, uh, where this little girl was molested.
只因一件小證物被污染了
And because of this one tiny piece of evidence...
他獲無罪釋放
...that was tainted, he walked.
賈卓士  他無罪釋放
Charles Gish walked away.
我卻無能為力
Nothing I could do about it.
他獲釋的那天晚上
The night after he was released...
瑪姬的父母回到家
...Margaret's parents came home.
這是那小女孩的名字  單瑪姬
That was the little girl's name, Margaret Sims.
他們發現賈卓士坐在客廳中
And they found Charles Gish sitting in their living room.
他在看電視
He was watching television...
瑪姬坐在他身旁
...and Margaret was sitting next to him...
他把她從中切開兩半
...and he had cut her open right down the middle.
父母還在冰箱中發現瑪姬的心臟
And the parents found Margaret's heart in the freezer.
卓士覺得他們可能想保存它留念
Charles figured they'd probably wanna keep it.
之後我便辭了職  加入聯邦密探
After that, I left the DA and joined the FBI.
我想嘗試捉拿他們
Figured I'd just try to catch them.
直到如今
Till now.
是的
Yeah.
我告訴你  史卡萊不再是史卡萊了
You know, I started to tell you that Stargher really isn't Stargher anymore.
那是真的  也是假的
Well, that's true, and it's not.
主要的部分仍是那恐怖的東西
The dominant side is still this horrible thing...
- 但也有正面的部分  - 正面的部分?
- ...but there's a positive side that-- - Positive side?
他視自己為兒童的那部分
Well, the way he sees himself as a child.
- 但那個是他嗎?  - 兒童史卡萊接觸我
- But isn't that him? - The boy Stargher made contact.
他對我好奇
He's curious about me.
我接近那孩子  或可知道茱莉下落
If I could reach the boy, then maybe he'd tell me about Julia.
賈卓士後來怎樣?
What ever happened to Charles Gish?
他因為精神病而逃過謀殺罪
Old Charlie beat the murder rap because, uh, he was insane when he killed Margaret.
他的律師把陪審團說得帖帖服服
His attorney, uh, milked the jury for all they were worth.
他說賈卓士自小遭到性侵犯  才令他走上這條路
Said that a life of sexual abuse drove him to do these things...
他媽的  什麼鬼話連篇
...and, you know, what ever the fuck. All that same old bullshit. Heh.
那為什麼是鬼話?
Why is that bullshit?
我相信一個孩子可以經歷
I believe a child can experience...
比賈卓士糟一百倍的性侵犯
...a hundred times worse the abuse than what Gish went through...
但仍然會長大  成為一個
...and still grow up to be somebody that would never, ever...
永遠永遠不會傷害別人的人
...ever hurt another living being.
你肯定嗎?
And you're sure of that?
是的
Yes, I am.
我肯定
I'm sure of that.
你去了哪裏?
Hey, where the hell you been?
我一直在這裏
I've been right here.
下次先告訴我好嗎?
Well, next time tell me, okay?
我不想打擾你
I didn't wanna disturb you. You looked so cute.
你睡相那麼可愛
You're all sleeping when you get that look on you.
你的同事想知道拿史卡萊怎麼辦
Your colleagues wanna know what to do with, uh, Stargher.
叫他們幫他準備好吧  我立刻到
Tell them to prep him. I'll be right there.
謝謝你  嘉芙
Thank you, Catherine.
史卡萊有沒有寵物?  貓狗之類?
Stargher have any pets? You know, cats, dogs...
你真乖啊  對嗎  華倫泰?
Yeah, you're a good boy, aren't you, Valentine?
- 那會有幫助嗎?  - 對  在潛意識的層面
- That's supposed to help? - On a subconscious level, yes.
任何對卡萊有意義  令他開心的事物
Anything that was special to Stargher, gave him pleasure...
都應該會令他較易接近
...should make him more accessible...
- 平靜的狀態  - 平靜?
...more peaceful. - Peaceful?
那樣就可以了
MIRIAM: That's enough, then.
- 警探  - 醫生
- MIRIAM: Mr. Novak. - Doctor.
- 謝謝  - 開始吧
- Thank you. - You got it.
第二回合
Round two.
亨利  這不好笑
CATHERINE: Henry, not funny.
- 怎麼啦?  - 一點也不好笑  亨利
- What's happening? - CATHERINE: Not funny, Henry.
- 嘉芙  - 別這樣  不要再玩了
- HENRY: Catherine. - Come on, stop playing around.
我沒開玩笑  這是電力故障
HENRY: I'm not. It's a power problem.
我們被鎖在外面了
We're locked out, Catherine.
你得檢查一下斷路器
I need you to check the circuit breaker.
你去檢查電路六至十二
I want you to check circuits six through 12.
- 快呀  起來  - 嗯哼
- Come on. Get up. - CATHERINE: Mm-hm.
六至十二
HENRY: Six through 12.
我已經進去了
I'm already in.
她說什麼?
What did she say?
華倫泰
Valentine.
CATHERINE: Valentine.
過來  乖
Come here, boy.
華倫泰
Valentine.
你可以帶我去見卡萊嗎?
Can you take me to Carl?
需要幫忙嗎?
Need some help?
我有份禮物給你
I've got a present for you.
如果你需要我
If you need me...
或者你覺得我在附近  卻找不到我
...or if you feel like I'm around, but you can't find me, just...
只要用這個反射光線就行
Shine it like this.
拿去吧
Go ahead, take it.
喜歡嗎?
You like it?
- 卡萊?  - 什麼事?
- CARL'S FATHER: Carl? - What's the matter?
有什麼不妥?
What? What's wrong?
這裏發生什麼事?  那碟子是自己破的嗎?
CARL'S FATHER: What happened over here? Just broke all by itself.
- 是不是你打破的?  - 是我打破的
- Did you break that plate? - CATHERINE: I broke the plate.
- 碟子是不是你打破的?  以為我很多錢嗎? - 是我打破的
- Did you break that plate? - I broke the plate.
我們把它們全打破吧  怎麼樣?
Well, hey. Let's break them all, how about that?
他媽的  你這個大話精!
You little fucking liar!
該把你像發育不全的畜牲般淹死
I should've drowned you like the runt of the litter.
在我家不准說謊  這是我的家
You don't lie in my house. This is my house!
不是我給他的
[WOMAN SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY]
洋娃娃是女孩的  不能給男孩玩
CARL'S FATHER: A doll? Those are for girls, you dumb whore.
- 只是玩具而已  - 閉嘴  八婆
- WOMAN: It's just a toy. - CARL'S FATHER: Shut up!
你不是他親生媽媽  她不是你媽媽
You're not his mother! She's not your mother.
你媽媽拋棄了我們  你要記住
She left us, Carl. Remember that.
看到了嗎?  看到了嗎?
See that? See that?
這裏是
That is...
邪惡之地
...a place of evil.
混蛋
What the fucking cripes?
老天爺
Jesus Christ.
這他媽的是什麼?  過來
What the fuck is this? Get back, get over here!
玩洋娃娃?  你這個小基佬
Playing with dolls? You little faggot!
你是什麼?  女人嗎?
What are you, some kind of a woman? Get up!
- 可是  爸  啊  - 他媽的
- CARL: But, Dad-- Aah! - CARL'S FATHER: Damn it.
你想哭嗎?
You want something to cry about?
給你一個哭的理由吧  女人
I'll give you something to cry about, woman!
- 啊  - 女人型
- CARL: Aah! - Mama's boy!
我養的不是基佬!
I didn't raise no faggot!
天啦
Christ.
不准再哭  你想像女人般熨衣服嗎?
Stop your crying. You wanna iron like a woman?
- 讓我教你怎樣像女人般熨衣服吧  - 不
- Let me show you how to iron. - CATHERINE: No!
救命
WOMAN: Help me.
她
CARL: She...
她是我的第一個
She was my first.
我弄得一塌糊塗
And I made such a mess.
不知道自己在幹什麼
Didn't know what I was doing.
你為什麼會在這裏?
Why are you here?
不要說謊
Don't lie.
- 我來幫你的  - 你撒謊
- I came to help you. - You're lying.
婊子  賤人
Bitch. Whore.
爛屄
Cunt!
你說話就像你爸爸
You sound like your father.
他一文不值  他一文不值
[DISTORTED VOICE] He was nothing. He is nothing.
誰叫你那麼說的?
Who told you to say that?
你記得他第一次跟你說話嗎?
Do you remember the first time he talked to you?
你當時在水中嗎?  也許你在游泳
Were you in water? Maybe you went swimming.
那是我的浸禮
It was my baptism.
我爸爸  他把我按入水底
My father, he pushed me under.
我當時幾乎心臟病發
I think I had some kind of seizure.
我以為我要淹死了  大家只是袖手旁觀
I think I was drowning, and everybody just looked at me.
沒有人救我  沒有人
Nobody helped me. Nobody.
除了他
Except him.
我爸爸
My father...
那晚帶我回家  打斷了我三條肋骨
...he took me home that night and he broke three of my ribs...
打裂了我的下顎
...and fractured my jaw.
當時我只有六歲
I was 6 years old.
卡萊
Carl.
你爸爸對你的行為是邪惡的
What your father did to you is evil.
是錯的
What he did to you was wrong.
- 他像對待死物似的對待你  - 不
- He treated you like a thing. - No.
他比我更強大
He was more powerful than me.
不對  沒有人應該受到那種對待的
No. No one should be treated like that.
是嗎?
Is that right?
那麼你的世界是怎樣的?
In what world do you live in?
- 卡萊  賀茱莉在哪裏?  - 不
- Carl, where is Julia Hickson? - No.
不准提名字
No names.
No names!
她在哪裏?
Where is she?
我瞭解你  卡萊  你想告訴我的
I know you, Carl. You wanna tell me.
你瞭解我?
[IN DISTORTED VOICE] You know me?
你知道我是誰嗎?
You know who I am?
她在哪裏?
Where is she?
茱莉在哪裏?
Where's Julia?
茱莉在哪裏  卡萊?
Where's Julia, Carl?
- 美琳  - 嗯哼?
- Miriam. - Mm-hm?
那一定有問題
That can't be right.
開到最大
MIRIAM: Danger pulse.
- 沒有變化  - 天呀
- No change. - Christ.
- 緊急中止好嗎?  - 不
- What about emergency cessation? - No.
中斷輸送器  關閉接收儀
Gradually terminate the feed, disable the receptors--
這會造成嚴重震盪的  關上那個
It could lead to massive shock. Could you please shut that thing off?
發生什麼事?
What's going on?
我跟你說過的那假設情況
HENRY: That hypothetical situation I told you about.
- 現在成真了  - 你不能中止它嗎?
- It's happening. - NOVAK: Can't you stop it?
沒那麼簡單
It's not that simple.
- 你以前中止過的  - 對  但情況不同  那是艾華
- You stopped it before-- - Yes, that was different. That was Edward.
史的內心是陌生世界  她迷失了
With Stargher, his mind is unfamiliar territory and she's lost.
- 她以為這是真的  - 我們有什麼可以做的?
- She thinks this is real. - NOVAK: Anything we can do?
我們做什麼都可能令情況更壞
Whatever we do runs the risk of making things worse for her.
好極了  那麼她就在某處迷失了
NOVAK: Worse. That's great. So she's lost somewhere?
亨利
Henry.
- 不行  不行  - 什麼不行?
- No.No. - No, what?
我需要你在這裏
I need you here.
他媽的停止  停止  停止
Fucking stop! Stop! Stop!
他媽的放我出去
Let me the fuck out!
我不想再困在這裏了
[SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
他媽的放我出去  放我出去
Let me the fuck out. Let me out!
放我出去  你這個變態賤人
Get me out, you sick fuck!
你去死吧  放我出去
Fuck you! Let me out.
救自己  救自己  茱莉
Do something. Do something to end this.
救自己
Do some-- Do something.
我覺得全身像爬滿蟲似的
I got bugs crawling all over my body.
感覺會越來越差
It gets worse.
你對這個完全沒有準備
You're completely unprepared for this.
- 靳醫生  這件事我們已討論過了  - 對  但我試過這個程序
- Dr. Kent, we've been over all this. - Yes, but I've been through the process.
她也試過這個程序  那沒有關係
She went through the process too and it didn't matter.
你不認識他
You don't know him.
好吧
Okay.
祝你好運
Be lucky.
來吧
Come on, guys.
預備好了嗎?
Ready?
彼得  最初幾分鐘
Uh, Peter, the first few minutes...
你會很迷失
...will be very disorienting.
記著要保持鎮定  集中精神
Remember to stay calm and focused.
直覺在這階段很重要  信任直覺
Instincts play a very important part here, so trust them.
- 要開始了  - 好
- We have to go. - Yeah. All right.
彼得  你看過她的檔案
Peter, you've read her file.
對她說一些很個人的事
Hit her with something personal.
記著  彼得  這不是真實的
And remember, Peter, it's not real.
搞什麼鬼?
What the fuck?
見到我兒子嗎?
Have you seen him? My boy? My little one?
- 他爸爸帶走了他  - 他是我那個洞屙出來的  了不起啊
- His father took him from me. - I spit him out my hole. Big deal.
- 並不意味著我不在乎他  - 我的孩子討厭死了  他沒有靈魂
- Don't mean I can't take care of him. - My child's an abomination. He has no soul.
好吧
Okay.
嘉芙
Catherine.
是你嗎?  你沒事吧?
Is that you? You all right?
嘉芙
Catherine.
- 彼得  - 聽我說
- CATHERINE [THINKING]: Peter. - Listen to me.
可憐的彼得
Poor Peter.
這不是真實的
This isn't real.
爸爸有沒有做壞事啊?
CATHERINE: Did daddy do a bad thing?
嘉芙  求求你聽我說
NOVAK [THINKING]: Catherine, please listen to me.
洛彼得
CATHERINE: Peter Novak.
我是聯邦密探
NOVAK: I Work With the FBI.
我們來此找賀茱莉
I'm here to find Julia Hickson.
別怕
CATHERINE: Don't be scared.
嘉芙  看看你手上的東西
This isn't real.
你記得嗎?
You remember that?
在你手上你可以按動的那東西?
嘉芙  聽我說
Catherine, listen to me.
嘉芙  我們是來找...
Catherine.
嘉芙
嘉芙  你得試著記起來
Catherine, you gotta try to remember.
你記得艾華嗎?
Do you remember Edward?
嘉芙
Catherine.
跟我說句話
Talk to me for a sec.
卑鄙小人
Naughty worm.
你去死吧  狗雜種
Fuck you! Fuck you, motherfucker!
嘉芙  他媽的快醒過來
Catherine, wake the fuck up now!
母馬吃燕麥  雌鹿吃燕麥
[MUSIC BOX PLAYING AND CARL HUMMING]
小綿羊吃常春藤
小山羊也吃常春藤
你會吃嗎?
[SINGS INDISTINCTLY]
嘉芙
Catherine!
在你念大學時
When you were in college...
你弟弟發生車禍
...your baby brother had a car accident!
他昏迷了六個月才去世
He was in a coma for six months before he died!
很抱歉我要提起這件事
And I'm sorry for saying that!
但你得醒過來啊
But you gotta wake up!
天啊
God!
這不是真實的
It's not real.
這不是真的
這不是真實的  不是真實的
"It's not real! It's not real! Not real!
不是真實的
Not real! Not real!"
彼得
Peter.
- 沒事了  - 他媽的發生了什麼事?
- It's okay. - What the fuck happened?
我們在哪裏?
Where are we?
噢  天吶
CATHERINE: Oh, my God.
這就是他囚禁她的地方嗎?
Is this where he keeps them?
卡萊  沒事了
Carl. Oh, it's okay.
茱莉
NOVAK: Julia.
不要怕
CATHERINE: Don't be scared.
我永遠不會傷害你的  我是你的朋友
I would never hurt you. I'm your friend.
彼得也是朋友
And Peter, he's a friend too.
你知道這地方在地圖上的哪裏嗎?
Do you know where this place is? Like on a map?
嗯
Mm.
我真為你驕傲
CATHERINE: I am so proud of you.
(雕刻家)
即使彼得找不到茱莉
Even if Peter doesn't find Julia...
- 我也答應我會回來幫你  - 嘉芙
- ...I promise I will come back and help you. - Catherine!
嘉芙
Catherine!
- 你幹什麼?  - 我們走吧
- What are you doing? - Let's go.
- 卡萊  - 我見到她  我知道她下落了  走吧
- Carl. - I saw her. I know how to find Julia.
- 我不可以把他留在這裏  - 他媽的  嘉芙  我們走吧
- I just can't leave him here! - Goddamn it, Catherine, let's go!
- 卡萊  - 我知道怎樣找她了
- CATHERINE: Carl! - I know how to find her.
- 不  卡萊  - 我們一定要回去  沒時間了
- No! Carl. - We gotta go back. We're running out of time.
不  我們不可以離開他  回去
CATHERINE: No!
- 我們快走吧  求求你  - 我會回來找你的  卡萊
- NOVAK: Let's go back! Please! - I'll come back for you, Carl!
- 我發誓我一定會回來的  - 嘉芙  我們現在就要走了
- I promise I'll come back! - NOVAK: Catherine, we gotta go now!
- 他回來了 - 嘉芙怎麼樣?
- RAMSEY: That means he's back. - MIRIAM: How's Catherine?
慢慢來  彼得
Take it easy, Peter.
她沒事吧?
Is she okay?
放鬆點  彼得  慢慢呼吸
Take it easy, Peter. Just breathe.
- 她沒事嗎  - 是的  我想她沒事
- Is she okay? - Yeah, I think she is.
他媽的  你能幫我脫掉這個嗎?
Can you get me out of this fucking suit?
我接個電話
Let me get this.
- 我是高爾  - 高爾  我是彼得
- Yeah, Cole here. - Cole, it's Novak.
情況怎麼樣?
Yeah, what's up?
下去地窖  史卡萊的工作室
I want you to go down to the basement...
你在那裏打給我
...at Stargher's workplace and call me when you get down there.
- 他們還在調查  - 別理他媽的調查
- They haven't finished the grid. - Fuck the grid.
- 去那裏打給我  - 你沒事吧?
- Call me when you get there. - RAMSEY: You okay?
- 沒事  - 想告訴我發生什麼事嗎?
- I'm fine. - What happened in there?
- 媽的  - 你痛嗎?
- Oh, fuck. - You in pain?
- 發生什麼事?  - 他媽的  我見到她了
- What happened, Peter? - Fuck. I saw her.
- 你見到誰?  - 我知道去哪裏找她
- Who? - I know where to find her.
- 誰?  - 茱莉  我知道她在哪裏  我見到她
- Who? - Julia. I know where to find her.
你為什麼不讓靳醫生看你一下?
Okay. Why don't you come and, uh, let Dr. Kent have a look at you?
彼得?
Pete?
- 高爾?  - 我是高爾
- Cole? - Yeah, this is Cole. Uh...
我下來這裏幹嘛?
Now, what am I doing down here?
那張他用的鐵床  上面有座吊車
That machine that he uses, there's a hoist.
我想讓你
I want you to look for a, uh, plaque...
找一塊金屬板  上面有商標的
...or a metal plate with some sort of logo on it.
我找到了
Yeah, I got it.
寫著雕刻家工業用品
Uh, it's Carver industrial equipment...
地址是加洲貝加士菲市
...in, uh, Bakersfield, California.
我要你盡量找出
Okay. I want you to find out every goddamn thing...
那機器的資料
...that you can about that machine.
用家  賣家  買家
Who used it, who sold it, who bought it.
盡量找
Just find out everything you can.
我待會在直升機打給你
I'm gonna call you from the chopper in about 20 minutes.
讓我看看  很好
MIRIAM: All right, let me have a look. Good.
很好
That's good.
- 那聯邦密探走了  - 什麼?
- HENRY: The FBI has left the building. - What?
我還沒檢查彼得啊
I haven't had a chance to clear Novak!
你想我怎樣?
HENRY: What did you expect me to do?
- 我無法阻止他  - 行了
- HENRY: There's no way I could stop him. - CATHERINE: Go.
- 去檢查他吧  我沒事  - 你肯定?  讓我看看
- I'm okay. Mm-hm. - Are you sure? Let me have a look.
拜託
Come on.
好吧
Okay.
- 好啦  - 好的
- All right. - Okay.
很好
Okay.
說話啊
RAMSEY: Peter, just talk to me.
若那是你的幻覺怎麼辦?
What if your mind is playing tricks on you?
注射了那麼多藥  那可能是幻覺
They shot you full of drugs, Peter. Who knows if what you saw is real?
嘉芙?
Catherine?
嘉芙  開門
Catherine, open this door.
嘉芙
Catherine.
- 我發誓  - 你在幹什麼?
- CATHERINE: I promise... - HENRY: What are you doing?
- 我要幫你  - 不
- ...I'm gonna help you. HENRY: No.
別摧毀你的事業
Do not jeopardize your career.
這是未經批准的程序  你知道的
You're not authorized to be here, you know that.
這很危險  你為什麼要這樣做?
It's dangerous. What are you doing?
(不准進入)
- 美琳  - 她在幹什麼?
- HENRY: Miriam. - What's she doing?
- 你知道她在幹什麼的  - 我的天
- You know what she's doing. - MIRIAM: For Christ's sake.
嘉芙  天呀
Catherine! Jesus.
她更改了密碼  你進不去的
HENRY: She's changed the codes. You can't get in.
怎麼回事
What happened?
- 她逆轉了輸送器  - 什麼意思?
- She reversed the feeds. - RAMSEY: What does that mean?
那程序本來是讓她進入他內心的
The process is intended for her to go into his mind.
但現在她要將他帶進她的內心
But instead, she's bringing him into hers.
不會吧
Come on!
我答應過會回來幫你的
I promised I'd come back and help you.
看  我一定會遵守諾言
See, I always keep my promises.
我可以留在這裏嗎?  跟你一起?
Can I stay here with you?
不  不  甜心  對不起  那樣做是不行的
No, honey, I'm sorry. It doesn't work that way.
我沒有辦法
There's nothing I can do about that.
有的
CARL [IN ADULT VOICE]: Yes, there is.
在我還是孩子的時候
When I was a little boy...
我發現了一隻小鳥
...I found this bird.
它受傷了
And he was injured...
斷了一條腿或什麼的
...had a broken leg or something.
我爸爸知道了這件事
Well, my father found out that I had it.
我知他一定會對它做出可怕的事
And I knew that he would do something horrible to it.
那只是時間問題而已
It was just a matter of time.
所以我在洗碗盆中淹死了它
So I took it to the sink and I held it under.
那對它來說還好一點
It was better for the bird.
我救了它
I saved him.
我不能那樣做  卡萊
I can't do that, Carl.
我不會那樣做
I won't.
不要緊的
It doesn't matter.
他找到我了
He found me.
他總會找到我的
He always finds me.
洛探員  請通話
Agent Novak? Go ahead.
- 高爾?  - 我是高爾  聽著
- Cole? - COLE: Yeah, Novak, listen to this.
吊車賣了給一個姓斑的人
The hoist was sold to a guy named Bainbridge...
他想在迪蘭盧附近開一間機器廠
...who tried to build a machine works out near Delano.
他後來破產  州政府接管了廠房
Bainbridge ends up in bankruptcy court and the state winds up with the land.
猜猜州政府雇了誰去封閉廠房
And guess who they hire to seal the place up.
- 你在開玩笑  - 不  我不喜歡開玩笑
- Oh, you're fucking kidding me. - No. I'm not the kidding type.
是史卡萊
Carl Rudolph Stargher.
- 那在哪裏?  - 九十九號公路十號出口
- Where's the land? - Exit 10, off Highway 99.
- 我們立即出發  - 我知道在哪裏
- We're on our way now. - Got it. I know where that is.
救命
Help! Help me!
是這兒了
PILOT: This is the area.
我的世界  我的規則
CATHERINE [THINKING]: My world, my rules.
下手吧
Do it.
這不是真實的
It's not real.
我的天  天呀
Me-god boy-
天呀  我的天
Boy me-god.
你無法殺死我的
You cannot kill me.
寶貝  沒事的
It's okay.
救我
Save me.
留在這裏跟我一起吧
You can stay here with me.
嘿
Hey. Hey!
沒事了
Hey! It's okay.
沒事了  你要離玻璃遠一點
It's okay. It's okay. You've gotta back away.
游去後面  去後面  去後面  茱莉
Swim to the back. Back away! Back up from here. Back up!
亨利
Henry.
沒事的
It's okay.
沒事了
Are you okay? You okay?
你沒有事了  你安全了  沒事了
You're okay. You're okay. Hey. Hey. You're okay.
- 林西探員?  - 我是林西
- MAN [OVER RADIO]: Agent Ramsey? - Yeah, Ramsey.
她來了
MAN: She's here.
好  讓她進來
RAMSEY: Okay, let her through.
外面有人找你
Somebody outside for you.
她來幹嘛?
What is she doing here?
她想看看他的家
Said she wanted to see his home.
那真奇怪
NOVAK: It's pretty strange.
她還養著他的狗
She's keeping his dog.
真他媽的奇怪
Pretty fucking strange is par for the course.
我幾乎認不出你
I almost didn't recognize you.
你何時恢復平民身份?
How long do you get to be a civilian?
幾星期
A couple weeks...
待案件結束後  再看看怎樣
...until after the inquiry and see what happens.
林西告訴我  你想...
Ramsey told me you were thinking of, uh...
那個叫什麼?
What do you call that thing?
- 逆轉  - 逆轉
- Reversal? - Reversal.
- 跟那個在協助的孩子嗎?  - 是的  他叫艾華
- With the, uh, kid you were working with? - Yeah. Edward.
艾華
Edward.
你肯定你想這麼做嗎?
Are you sure you wanna do that?
絕對肯定
Absolutely.
你不擔心會發生什麼事嗎?
You're not worried about what might happen?
我永遠不會做傷害艾華的事
I would never do anything to hurt Edward.
我不是擔心他
It wasn't him I was worried about.
你呢?  你好嗎?
What about you? How are you?
我不大肯定
I'm not sure. I...
我記得零零碎碎的片斷
I kind of remember pieces of everything.
據聯邦調查局所稱
According to the FBI, um...
你們給我注射了影響思想的藥物
...you guys put me on some drug-fueled mind-bender...
令我想起一個我已有的記憶
...which then, uh, triggered a memory I already had...
據官方紀錄
...and officially we found Julia Hickson...
我用傳統方法破案
...through good old-fashioned detective work.
我想我該說再見了
I guess this is hello and goodbye, then.
我想是的
I guess so.
感謝一切  嘉芙
Thanks for everything, Catherine.
保重
- Be safe. - All right.
片名: 入 侵 腦 細 胞
港譯: 移 魂 追 兇
台譯: 死 亡 空 間